in this video we're going to talk about
how to solve physics problems
associated with
the beak frequency
whenever two sound waves with a
frequency that's very close to each
other
whenever they're close together they can
produce the beat frequency and to
calculate this beat frequency
it's simply the absolute difference
of the two frequencies
so it's going to be 436
minus 425
so in this example
the beat frequency is 11 hertz
and so that's all you got to do for this
problem
here's the second problem
a sound wave at a frequency of 360 hertz
produces 32 beats in four seconds when
interacting with a vibrating tuning fork
what is the beat frequency
so frequency
is defined as the number of cycles that
occur per second
so if you take the cycles and divide it
by the time
then you can get the frequency in this
example the cycles are the number of
beats
so there's 32 beats
that occur in a time period of 4 seconds
so the beat frequency
is 32 divided by 4 which is
8 beats per second
so that's the b frequency
what are the two possible frequencies of
the vibrating tuning fork
so the vibrating tuning fork is going to
be
8 hertz away from this particular sound
wave
it can be 360 plus 8 which is 368 hertz
or
it could be 360 minus 8
which is 352 hertz
so this frequency with this one will
produce a b frequency of eight because
they differ by eight units
and if these two are next to each other
they will also produce a b frequency of
eight
so the two and four can be any one of
these two numbers
number three
a tuning fork produces a beat frequency
of five hertz
with a 415 hertz sound wave
when placed near a sound wave
oscillating at 426 hertz
a beat frequency of 6 hertz is generated
what is the frequency of the tuning fork
so let's focus on the 415 frequency
if a beat frequency of 5 hertz
is produced
with this sound and a tuning fork that
means the frequency of the 24 could be
two numbers it could be 415 minus 5
which is 410
or it could be 415 plus 5 which is 420
now
when placing a tuning fork next to a 426
hertz
sound
the beat frequency is six hertz so it
could be 426 plus six which is 432
or it could be 426 minus 6 which is 420.
in order to produce a beat frequency of
five and six with these
two sound waves
then the tuning fork has to be 420
because that's the only frequency
that
matches
with these two values
it's the only one that's the same for
both of them
so that's the frequency of the tuning
fork that's how you can find it